In this video, we're going to transition from lexical analysis to parsing and talk
在这段视频中，我们将从词汇分析过渡到解析和交谈
a little bit about the relationship between those two compiler phases. We've
稍微了解一下这两个编译器阶段之间的关系。我们已经
already talked about regular languages and it's worth mentioning that these are the
我已经讨论过常规语言，值得一提的是，这些是
weakest formal languages that are widely used. But they have, of course, many
被广泛使用的最弱的正式语言。但是，当然，他们有很多
applications, some of which we saw in previous videos. The difficulty with
应用程序，其中一些我们在前面的视频中看到过。它的困难之处在于
regular languages is that a lot of languages are simply not regular. And
规则语言就是很多语言根本就是不规则的。和
there's some pretty important languages that can't be expressed using regular
有一些非常重要的语言不能用常规语言来表达
expressions or finite automata. So let's consider this language which is the set of
表达式或有限自动机。让我们考虑一下这门语言，它是
all balanced parentheses. So some elements of this language would be at the string
所有的括号都是对齐的。因此，这种语言的某些元素会在字符串中
one open-paren, one close-paren, two open-parens, two close-parens, three
一个左右手，一个左右手，两个左右手，两个左右手，三个
open-parens, three close-parens and so on. And, you can imagine that this is actually
左右撇子、三个右撇子，以此类推。你可以想象这实际上是
something that's fairly representative of lots of programming language construct. So
一些相当能代表大量编程语言构造的东西。所以
for example, any kind of nested arithmetic expression would fit into this class but
例如，任何类型的嵌套算术表达式都适合此类，但是
also things like nested if and else's will have this category, this characteristic.
像嵌套的if和Else这样的东西也会有这个类别，这个特征。
And here with the nested [inaudible] it's just the f statement, the functions like
这里嵌套的[听不见]只有f语句，函数如下
an open-paren. Not every languages like cool which has the explicit closing fee as
一位敞开心扉的帕伦。并不是每种语言都像Cool一样，它有明确的结束费，比如
well but they're implicit in many languages and so there are lots of nesting
嗯，但是它们在许多语言中都是隐含的，所以有很多嵌套
structure in programming languages constructs and those cannot be handled by
结构在编程语言构造中，而这些构造不能由
regular expressions. So this raises the question of what the regular languages can
正则表达式。因此，这就提出了一个问题，即常规语言可以
express. And, why they aren't sufficient for recognizing arbitrary nesting
快递。还有，为什么它们不足以识别任意嵌套
structure. So we can illustrate the limitations of regular languages and
结构。所以我们可以说明常规语言的局限性
Finite Automaton by looking a simple two state machine. So let's consider this
通过看一个简单的双状态机来实现有限自动机。所以让我们考虑一下这个
machine. We have one we have start state and then the other state is the accepting
机器。我们有一个状态，我们有开始状态，然后另一个状态是接受
state. And, we'll have this machine. Just be a machine that we've already seen
州政府。还有，我们要买这台机器。只是做一台我们已经见过的机器
actually and it'll recognize strings with odd numbers of 1's. So if we see a one and
实际上，它会识别带有奇数个1的字符串。所以如果我们看到一个1和
we're in the start state, we move. We now see an odd number of 1's. We move to the
我们处于开始状态，我们开始行动。我们现在看到奇数个1。我们移到
accepting state and we stay there until we see another one. In which case, we've seen
接受状态，我们呆在那里直到我们看到另一个状态。在这种情况下，我们已经看到
even number of 1's and then we're in the start state. So whenever we see an odd
偶数个1，然后我们就处于开始状态。所以每当我们看到奇怪的
number of 1's, we're in the final state. Whenever we see an even number of 1's,
数到1，我们就到最后状态了。每当我们看到偶数个1的时候，
we're in the start state. And if we feed this a fairly long string of 1's, let's,
我们现在处于启动状态。如果我们输入一串相当长的1，让我们，
let's select only seven 1's in it. Then what's it going to do is going to go back
让我们只选择其中的七个1。那么它要做的就是回到
and forth and back and forth between these states. It's gonna wind up in the final
在这些州之间来来回回。它会在决赛中结束
state when it gets to the last one so it'll accept but notice that it doesn't
当它到达最后一个时声明，这样它就会接受，但请注意，它不会
know how many times it's been to that final state. It doesn't remember the
知道它已经到达那个最终状态多少次了。它不记得
length of the string; it doesn't have any way of counting how many characters the
字符串的长度；它没有任何方法来计算
string had in it. And in fact, all I can count here is the parity. So in general
绳子在里面。事实上，我在这里所能计算的就是奇偶性。所以大体上来说
Finite Automata can really only express things where you can count modulus on k.
有限自动机实际上只能表示可以计算k上的模数的东西。
So they can count mod k for some k where k is the number of states in the machine.
所以他们可以计算mod，k，这里k是机器中的状态数。
And so, you know if I have pre-test the machine, I can keep track of whether the
所以，你知道，如果我预先测试了机器，我可以跟踪
string length is divisible by three or some other similar property but I can't do
字符串长度可以被3或其他类似属性整除，但我不能这样做
things like count to an arbitrary i so if I need to recognize a language that
像任意的I这样的东西，所以如果我需要识别一种语言，
requires counting arbitrarily high like recognizing all strings of balance
需要任意高的计数，就像识别所有的平衡字符串一样
parentheses, we can't do that with the finite set of states. So what does a
括号中，我们不能用有限的状态集做到这一点。那么，一个
parser do, it takes the sequence of tokens as input from the lexer and it produces a
解析器这样做，它从词法分析器获取标记序列作为输入，并生成一个
parse tree of the program. And for example in cool, here's an input expression that
程序的解析树。例如，在COOL中，这里有一个输入表达式，它
is input to the lexical analyzer. The lexical analyzer produces this sequence of
输入到词法分析器。词法分析器生成以下序列
tokens as its output. That's the input to the parser. Then the parser produces this
令牌作为其输出。这是解析器的输入。然后解析器生成以下内容
parse tree where the nesting structure has been made explicit. So, we have the, if
解析树，其中嵌套结构已显式显示。所以，我们有，如果
and else and then the three components: the predicate, the then branch and the
然后是三个组件：谓词、THEN分支和
else branch of the, if To summarize, the lexer takes a string of character as input
的Else分支，如果要总结，词法分析器接受字符串作为输入
and produces a string of tokens as output. That string of tok ens is the input to the
并产生一串令牌作为输出。该令牌Ens字符串是
parser which takes a string of tokens and produces a Parse Tree of the program. And
解析器，它接受一串令牌并生成程序的解析树。和
it's worth mentioning a couple of thing here. First of all, sometimes the Parse
这里值得一提的是几件事。首先，有时语法分析
Tree is only implicit. So the, a compiler may never actually build the full Parse
树只是隐式的。因此，编译器可能永远不会真正构建完整的Parse
Tree. We'll talk more about that later. Many compilers do build an explicit parse
树。我们稍后会详细讨论这一点。许多编译器确实构建了显式解析
tree but many do not. The other thing that's worth mentioning is that there are
树，但很多人没有。另一件值得一提的是，有
compilers that do combine these two phases into one where everything is done by the
编译器将这两个阶段合并为一个阶段，其中所有工作都由
parser. So, the parsing technology is generally powerful enough to express
解析器。因此，解析技术通常足够强大，可以表达
lexical analysis in addition to parsing. But most compilers still divide up the
除了解析之外，还可以进行词法分析。但是大多数编译器仍然将
work this way because regular expressions are such a good match for lexical analysis
这样做是因为正则表达式与词法分析非常匹配
and then the parsing is handled separately.
然后分别进行解析。